WILLIAM TRAN

Alhambra, CA 91801 ■ (626)589-2059 ■ wtran4hire@gmail.com
■ www.wtran.me ■ www.github.com/wtran29 ■ www.linkedin.com/in/william-tran

Career Profile

Focused Software Developer responsible for managing the exchange of data between the server and user, by building exciting applications that provide value to its users with technology and analytics. Past Finance/Accounting professional with +10 years of experience in compiling and handling large data sets.

Core competencies include Python, Django, Flask, PyCharm IDE, Java, Maven, Tomcat, Spring Boot, STS IDE, JavaScript, SQL, Node.js, Express.js, Angular5, jQuery, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite, Firebase, AWS EC2, S3 Storage, Ubuntu, Gunicorn, Nginx, OWASP, IAM Auth, Stripe API, Google API.

Familiar with C#, Unity, Visual Studios, React-Redux, React-Native, Android Studios, Pandas, Matplotlib, Numpy, Octave, Jupyter, Analytics, Mailchimp.

Professional Experience

WTRAN.ME -- Los Angeles, CA

Python/Django Developer, Nov 2017 to Current

- Designed, developed, tested, deployed, maintain and improved personalized portfolio website.
- Implemented fake news blog web app onto site as a demo to test functionality, including REST API.
- Integrated PostgreSQL database to store projects, blogs and comments.
- Leveraged Django for authorization, authentication and session handling to create blog and comments.
- Created front-end design using Bootstrap and JavaScript.
- PCMICROSTORE.COM -- Los Angeles, CA

Python Developer, Dec 2018 to Current

- Increased the company's productivity by providing a script to perform ETL processes.
- Developed web scraping in-house tool for company by creating a script that extracts deals, sorting by price points, transforming the data and loading it into Excel files.
- Implemented Beautifulsoup4 and Selenium tools to parse through, test and collect the data.
- Created algorithm to compare/remove duplicate data sets and timer to perform web scrap tasks at recurring times of the day.
- CROWDBOTICS -- Berkeley, CA

Software Developer, May 2018 to May 2018

- Developed and tested 5 landing pages to start AdWords campaign with pure CSS, Bootstrap and HTML.
- Collaborated with UI/UX Designer to build mobile and desktop responsiveness.
- Collaborated with developers using GitHub from multiple branches in an Agile environment.
- CLUB OF DIAMONDS -- Los Angeles, CA

JavaScript Developer, Nov 2017 to Mar 2018

- Configured MongoDB, RxJS and JSON routing, to pass data between models, controller and views, modularizing Node.js backend and Angular.
- Implemented registration, authentication, encryption, validations, sessions management, error handling.
- Implemented filter directive for search bar and equal validator directive for password confirmation.
- THE OLSON COMPANY -- Seal Beach, CA

Financial Analyst/Staff Accountant, Sep 2013 to Jun 2017

- Implemented conditional statements to automate calculations for the monthly prepaid insurance schedule which increased efficiency by 30%.
- Analyzed loan approval packages and managed loan draws to ensure funding of our projects.
- Managed revenue projection reports, profitability, cash flows, P&L impacts, investment packages.
- Compiled data related to land development, operations, legal, marketing and finance.
- ⇒ For more projects, please visit my portfolio website at www.wtran.me.

WILLIAM TRAN

Alhambra, CA 91801 ■ (626)589-2059 ■ wtran4hire@gmail.com ■ www.wtran.me ■ www.github.com/wtran29 ■ www.linkedin.com/in/william-tran

Education & Credentials

CAL POLY POMONA -- Pomona, CA

CODING DOJO -- Burbank, CA

BS in Finance

Full Stack Development Program

Certification:

- Redis Labs RU101 Certificate | Redis University
- Coding Dojo | Full Stack Development
- Complete Python Master Class
- Python for Finance: Investment Fundamentals & Data Analytics
- Machine Learning | Stanford University | Coursera

Recent Training and Seminars:

- Algorithms I | Princeton University | Coursera
- Machine Learning with Python